♪ ♪
( FAINT RUMBLING )
( RUMBLING INTENSIFIES )
( WHOOSHING )
( OBJECTS CLANKING )
( LOUD THUD )
( OBJECTS CONTINUE CLANKING )
♪ ♪
- ( INDISTINCT VOICES OVER COMM ) - ( RHYTHMIC BEEPING )
MIRANDA : This is Dr. Miranda North ,
quarantine officer on board the International Space Station .
Today the Pilgrim capsule , with its valuable Mars soil samples ,
completes its eight-month return from Mars .
Preparing to receive these samples
has been the purpose of our mission these last few months .
But the Pilgrim capsule is damaged .
At 0630 UTC , Pilgrim was struck by debris and veered off course .
Rory Adams will spacewalk to establish visual contact
with the incoming space capsule ,
and he will grab it with a remote arm .
We 've been waiting a long time for this sample ,
and Rory is placing himself at great risk to secure it .
Over and out .
DAVID : EMU at 4.7 psi , pure O2 .
RORY : Is that how you 're gonna do it ? I wouldn 't do it that way .
KAT : Dr. Jordan , status ? RORY : Come on , faster , faster , faster .
DAVID : Nitrogen at near zero .
KAT : Dr. North ? MIRANDA : I 'm in the airlock .
RORY : Faster , faster , faster . Come on .
KAT : Rory , slow to go fast .
RORY : Or fast to go fast . KAT : Deliberate .
RORY : What does she have against fast ?
KAT : Remember , eight billion people .
MIRANDA : Rory , if you can 't save it ...
RORY : Yeah , spoiler alert . I 'm fucking saving it .
MIRANDA : But if you can 't , Rory , just push the capsule into deep space , okay ?
- Do you hear me ? - RORY : Can you get OCD ...
Sorry , CDC out of my face ?
'Cause I got a big operation . I need to concentrate .
- MIRANDA : I just want you ... - I can 't ... I can 't hear you ...
- I love you , too . - ... at all .
DAVID : EMU at 4.7 psi , pure O2 .
Where 's the remote ?
- Here . The arm 's yours . - There you go .
- Full manual . - All right , he knows . Let 's go .
SHO : Careful with ... Sorry , you know this .
Yeah , yeah . No more sorries .
- KAT : Miranda , to the Cupola , please . - All right , that 's it .
Yep .
- ♪ ♪ - ( WHIRRING )
( SLOW , STEADY BEEPING )
♪ ♪
KAT : ( OVER COMM ) David ? Are you on your way ?
On my way .
- Slow , Sho . - SHO : Excuse me .
How do you say " breathe " in Japanese ?
Kokyu shiro .
This was supposed to be routine .
RORY : ( OVER COMM ) The airlock is sealed .
I am walking .
KAT : 4 : 35 UTC .
After striking debris , Pilgrim non-responsive .
Inbound on collision course with ISS .
Initiating emergency course correction and manual retrieval .
SHO : Canadarm online .
Transferring control to wireless .
KAT : Station to Control .
- Initiating sequence . - GROUND CONTROL : Affirmative .
SHO : So , the committee ?
KAT : You let me worry about the committee .
Where 's Rory ?
He is at risk out there .
RORY : Easy , folks . Mics are live .
You ready , Sho ?
SHO : Thrusters up .
( RUMBLING )
( BEEPING )
RORY : Moving into position .
I have control of the arm .
♪ ♪
HUGH : Your worry lines are showing .
Yeah , well , I get paid by the line .
- HUGH : I have a good feeling about this . - Yeah ?
HUGH : Rory 's gonna deliver that sample .
MIRANDA : Right to your lab .
( LIGHT RUMBLING )
( CREAKING )
KAT : Prepare for course correction .
.050-niner by.076.
- Remember your training . - We never trained for this .
KAT : On my mark . Five , four , three , two , one .
( CLICK , BEEP )
( DEEP RUMBLING , SHUDDERING )
( BEEPING , WHIRRING )
( RUMBLING , SHUDDERING GRADUALLY STOP )
KAT : New capsule trajectory , negative 0.50 .
AUTOMATED VOICE : Proximity alert . Proximity alert .
KAT : Ignore the proximity alert .
New station trajectory , negative.32.
The capsule will miss us . Just .
- Rory ? - I 'm still downrange .
And it 's coming in shallow .
Any moment now . Eight , maybe nine o 'clock .
I 'm having fun .
- Are you guys having fun ? - DAVID : Rory , if you miss ...
Yeah , yeah , yeah .
If ...
Just gonna skip off the atmosphere like a flat stone on water .
Just fly off into nowhere . It 's no harm done .
RORY : ( EXHALES ) Okay .
There .
- There . - RORY : I see it .
All right , here we go , here we go , here we go .
This is fun .
SHO : Rory , you have to move . It 's gonna hit you .
- No , it 's not . - Please , Rory , move .
KAT : Station to Control .
Visual confirmation of Mars Capsule Pilgrim .
RORY : I used to play catcher , but only in tee-ball .
- MIRANDA : Rory ? - Not now .
Not now . No , come on , come here , come here ,
come on , come on , come on .
( LOUD BOOM , DEEP RUMBLING )
( CREAKING , RATTLING )
Rory ?
- Rory ? - MIRANDA : Rory ?
( RORY LAUGHING )
HUGH : ( LAUGHS ) He got it . MIRANDA : Yes !
( RORY COUGHING , LAUGHING )
RORY : Oh , Hugh ?
Cue Instagram !
HUGH : I didn 't want to jinx it .
( RORY GRUNTS )
Point and shoot , motherfucker !
HUGH : ( CHUCKLES ) Okay , okay .
- ( CAMERA CLICKS , WHIRRS ) - ( RORY WHOOPS )
( RORY LAUGHS )
( RORY COUGHS )
RORY : Mars Capsule in locked position .
- ( SHO CHUCKLES ) - ( RORY WHOOPS )
( RORY LAUGHS )
Whoo ...
I 'm coming home .
This is Mission Commander Ekaterina Golovkina .
Tell the committee Pilgrim 's landed on Plymouth Rock .
The Mars samples are safe and sound .
Copy that , Commander .
Congratulations .
♪ ♪
( SQUEAKS SOFTLY )
( CLICKING )
HUGH : Ready ?
- ( ELECTRONIC DING ) - KAT : We are recording .
0640 UTC .
HUGH : Pilgrim wasn 't just seeing things in Mars ' soil .
We 're looking at a large single cell .
Inert .
Unmistakably biological .
And , like organisms on Earth ,
has what appears to be a nucleus , cytoplasm ...
( OVER COMM ) The cell wall is thick .
Those hairs look like cilia .
Longer than we 're used to seeing on Earth .
More like flagella .
- What 's our temperature ? - SHO : Minus 110 .
Start bringing it up .
SHO : Minus 82 .
HUGH : Even quicker .
SHO : Minus 55 .
This is some Re-Animator shit .
Oh , that 's a very obscure reference .
- Not for a nerd . - Not if you 're a nerd .
- ( HUGH CHUCKLES ) - SHO : Minus 17 .
Zero degrees .
HUGH : ( EXHALES ) Oh , come on .
SHO : Eighteen ...
Nineteen ...
20 degrees Celsius .
Nothing .
Update ?
I 'm gonna try a different atmosphere .
Closer to Proterozoic Earth than today 's Mars .
Less oxygen ...
More carbon dioxide .
- ( CLICK , BEEP ) - And then , when Sho 's ready ,
a growth medium .
In this case , glucose .
( PANTING )
( WHISPERS ) Come on , dance .
♪ ♪
MIRANDA : Did it just move ?
Hugh ?
HUGH : Oh .
( CHUCKLING SOFTLY )
HUGH : My God .
( GASPS )
MIRANDA : It worked . You woke it .
We 're looking at the first incontrovertible proof
of life beyond Earth .
( LAUGHS QUIETLY )
( CHUCKLING )
Oh , it 's beautiful .
♪ ♪
VARGAS : Our first question is from Allen . He 's nine years old .
And , Allen , what is your question for Commander Golovkina ?
Is it green ?
It isn 't visible at all , actually . It 's microscopic .
A single cell .
To put it into perspective , your body is made up of trillions .
There 's an alien inside of me ?
Oh , I bet your teacher sometimes thinks so .
MUIR : Well , we have another question from 8-year-old Mari .
Are you bringing the alien back to Earth ?
No , we 're gonna keep it up here . We 're gonna study it where it 's safe .
MUIR : Commander ?
The ISS is the most expensive house ever built .
$ 200 billion American and counting .
Because we keep adding rooms .
It flies around Earth 16 times a day .
In 30 years , over 100 people have lived here ,
thanks to generous countries like Russia , the USA , and China .
We call this Tranquility Node .
Dr. Jordan here is about to break the record for consecutive days in space .
Four hundred and seventy-three , straight .
Your mommy must miss you .
- ( LAUGHS ) - Ah , she does .
But I have family here .
Yeah , the kind that teases him 'cause his mommy misses him .
KAT : This is one of our newest crew members .
Miranda North from the Centers for Disease Control .
She 's a doctor , too .
You guys are witnessing a space triathlon .
Yeah , I 'm winning .
VARGAS : We have another question from 7-year-old Leila .
We think this question is a little personal .
- Go ahead . - How do you go to the bathroom ?
Funnel ,
tube ,
and some suction .
Everything we do on the ISS is like everything you do on Earth .
Except different . Do you like peas ?
ALLEN : Yep .
Mmm ! Mmm ! Mmm !
So , have you got a name yet ?
MUIR : For that , we want to go down live just outside our studio in Times Square
to one very brave classmate .
- VARGAS : Hi , Dominique . - Hi .
Calvin Coolidge Elementary
was chosen among 11,000 schools
- for this honor . - ( CROWD APPLAUDING )
We name the Martian
after our school .
" Calvin . "
( CHEERING )
RORY : Control ? Control ?
If you 're listening , and you probably are ,
'cause you 're creepy that way ,
can I just rant for a second about the micromanagement ?
We 're not blood-filled meat puppets .
I come from a long line of plumbers .
I can fix a shower .
If I can 't ... Well , Hugh doesn 't shower anyway ,
he 's British .
- First international incident . - I 'm not being critical of you .
You 're just a very under-bathed nation . Everybody knows it .
Don 't be an ugly American .
Wow . Who 's ugly now ?
I nailed Step 17 . I 'm a very good-looking American ,
you know ? Oh , I see , it 's right there .
Control , I 'm sorry about him .
KAT : Rory , Control can 't hear you .
I don 't know where rage like that comes from .
- Can you please fix the shower ? - Twenty-eight steps to fix a shower .
Ah . You know , I can do this myself .
No , I know . You just haven 't .
Doctors are always so bad at looking after themselves , aren 't they ?
( RAPID ELECTRONIC CLICKING )
( CLICKING STOPS )
You 've spent too much time up here , David .
Your atrophy 's accelerated .
And you 're close to your radiation limit .
You noticed any , um , glowing in the dark ?
( CHUCKLES )
DAVID : Hmm .
I like it up here .
When I was in the military , we 'd go to Syria .
You know .
We 'd set up a hospital ,
treat all the casualties , and then we 'd come back a week ...
A week or two later ,
and then the whole village would just be bombed out .
MIRANDA : Mmm .
Then Earth isn 't all Syria , though , is it ?
( RAPID BEEPING )
I can 't stand what we do to each other down there .
MIRANDA : But it 's home , and it 's beautiful .
Don 't you miss anything ?
Don 't you miss fresh water or birds
or the trees ?
- ♪ ♪ - ( LOW ELECTRONIC HUMMING )
I like the hum up here .
( DAVID INHALES DEEPLY )
And the air .
- Hmm . - ( LAUGHS SOFTLY )
KAT : What you have achieved with Calvin is remarkable , Hugh .
I haven 't had a chance to say that .
HUGH : Thank you .
I think these will prove to be the greatest days of my life .
I wish I had a time machine , so I could visit the 10-year-old me .
KAT : Did he want to be an astronaut ?
HUGH : He wanted out of the wheelchair .
KAT : And how does he feel now ?
Like a bird .
( CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
Oh , don 't get me wrong .
I don 't hate my chair .
I love it .
For the sake of the anonymous genius who invented it .
You 're one of a kind , Hugh .
( CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
Good night .
♪ ♪
- ( BEEP ) - SHO : 11 : 20 UTC .
HUGH : Hold on to your helmets . The glucose intake is very rapid .
( OVER COMM ) The specimen 's cells have begun to move together
en masse as a unit .
They 're also sharing electrical activity in what resembles a growing neural network .
Notice I didn 't say " brain . "
Dr. North speaking .
It is our educated opinion that this new species is not a colony
of fast-dividing single-celled organisms ,
but one larger , solitary organism
composed of trillions of identical cooperative cells .
Here 's what 's fascinating .
I mean , it 's all fascinating , isn 't it ?
Unlike most multicellular organisms ,
every cell of Calvin 's can perform every somatic function on its own .
Every single cell is
simultaneously a muscle cell
and a nerve cell and a photoreceptive cell .
So the creature , as a whole ,
is , in a very real sense , all muscle ,
all brain , all eye .
HUGH : As such , Calvin now possesses the means to interact with its environment ,
including the use of what appears to be proto-appendages .
I 'll demonstrate .
♪ ♪
( GASPS SOFTLY )
But notice how it 's approaching and not retreating .
HUGH : Its curiosity outweighs its fear .
♪ ♪
That 's beautiful .
( CHUCKLES )
♪ ♪
Hello , Calvin .
RORY : How 's that feel , Hugh ?
You 're gonna be a daddy .
There 's gonna be a big custody battle over this one .
- ( LAUGHTER ) - ( SINGING ) And if you feel
- Like I feel , baby - DAVID : One day , we 're all gonna die ,
and I want to know if there 'd be even the possibility of having ...
- Let 's get it on - ( LAUGHING )
Hey , let 's get it on ...
DAVID : I 'm getting a little nauseous .
( WOMAN SQUEALING IN PAIN )
You can do this , Kazumi .
I 'm doing my best .
It 's coming .
Any moment now , okay , push .
Easy for you to say .
You can do it , Kazumi .
( SQUEALING INTENSIFIES )
You can do it , you can do it .
Sho ...
I can see it . Okay , push .
It 's okay .
Push .
You 'll be able to meet Mei soon .
You can do it .
" ... and that there was more of it during the night . "
" We can observe , too , how the recollection of a dream , "
" which was still lively in the morning , "
" will melt away , except for a few small fragments ... "
RORY : This book doesn 't have pictures in it , does it ?
HUGH : Obviously not .
Would you prefer that I don 't read it out loud ?
- That 's beautiful . - HUGH : Beautiful .
( ALL LAUGHING )
- Oh , he makes me cry . - SHO : Hi , guys . Guys .
- Meet Mei . - ALL : Hey ! Oh !
( CHEERING , LAUGHING )
- Hi , Mei ! - HUGH : Hey , Mei !
- Say hi to everybody , Mei . - Hi , Mei .
HUGH : She 's beautiful ! RORY : Congratulations .
Thank you . Nice to meet you .
Do they have any idea who the father is ?
- Shut up . - HUGH : Another one , another one .
SHO : ( CHUCKLES ) Okay .
For story time .
It was my favorite .
You might say my first foray into space .
SHO : Oh , thank you so much . KAZUMI : Thank you , Commander .
- Thank you , guys . RORY : She 's beautiful , Sho .
Thank you !
- HUGH : Yay ! - No , seriously , that kid had blue eyes .
( ALL CHUCKLING )
♪ ♪
( SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
( CHUCKLES )
( SOFT , TREMBLING BREATHS )
♪ ♪
( RUMBLING )
( ALARM BLARING )
Fuck .
( RAPID BEEPING )
RORY : It 's the lab .
( ALARM CONTINUES BLARING )
( BEEPING )
( CLICK , BUZZ )
( WHOOSHING )
( CLOSES DOOR )
( KEYBOARD CLACKING )
( ALARM STOPS )
Okay . Miranda , check the O2 in the lab . Is it ...
O2 's on 21 . We 're clear for contamination .
We 're okay . Calvin 's safe .
I don 't understand how this happened .
Nothing in that lab can malfunction .
A clamp . It failed .
- It 's on me . - RORY : Yeah , no shit it 's on you .
A dizzy 5-year-old could have spotted that .
MIRANDA : Protecting these firewalls , yes , that 's my job .
But I can 't do it alone .
Kibo wasn 't designed for strict firewall lockdown ,
and neither was the station .
There is zero precedent for any of this .
But you do not come out of that lab without triple-checking everything .
You do not go into that lab without a proper rest .
For all I know , we 're carrying anthrax onboard .
You can 't compare Calvin to anthrax .
Yeah , I know at least five guys back home who can do my job .
( PANTING )
Nobody can do yours except you .
I don 't want to be around that thing . I 'm not qualified to be around that thing .
- HUGH : I understand . - Good .
I 'm just saying you can 't compare Calvin to anthrax .
RORY : Stop ... Stop calling it fucking " Calvin . "
We don 't know what that thing is . Yeah ?
And you 're in there , and you 're playing around with it
like it 's your buddy .
I 'm your buddy . You 're drunk on this . Wake up .
MIRANDA : This isn 't and will never be a controlled experiment .
So let 's all agree we made our first and last mistake .
I miss my fucking dog .
Good night .
♪ ♪
MIRANDA : Dr. Miranda North , quarantine officer , 2320 UTC .
After weeks of stunning growth and activity ,
Calvin is completely inactive .
We believe it 's likely due to the clamp failure in the lab ,
which caused a temporary change of air pressure in Calvin 's box .
Our working theory is that
this hibernation may be a defense mechanism .
Everyone here is on edge ,
and Hugh , of course , has been beating himself up ,
but , honestly , I 'm relieved .
Calvin was growing very fast ,
and this has now given me time
to reinforce firewall precautions with the crew .
The box must stay sealed , the lab must stay sealed ,
no matter the risk to Calvin .
HUGH : It 's just floating .
Because of my mistake in the lab .
And it was going so well .
- ( MIRANDA CHUCKLES SOFTLY ) - What ?
Something my dad used to say .
" It was all going so well . "
HUGH : I 'm toying with the idea of stimulating it electrically .
- What do you think ? - That 's not my call .
- But if it were ? - ( EXHALES )
I don 't know .
My job is lines of defense .
Imagine the worst thing that could ever happen ,
and then the worst after that ,
and the worst after that , and then I ...
- I 've planned for all of them . - HUGH : I understand that .
But risks are taken for reasons .
Because of Calvin , we 're gonna learn so much about life .
Its origin , its nature , maybe even its meaning .
- No , I know . - You 're a doctor .
Um , stem cell research .
What if Calvin could make stem cells obsolete ?
Help cure the incurable ...
Reverse the irreversible .
I have to fix this .
Good . Are you ready ?
- Stretch . - HUGH : Okay .
And relax .
- ( BEEPING ) - Ready .
- You sure it won 't hurt it ? - ( ELECTRICAL CRACKLE )
It 's a very , very low voltage .
We 're only stimulating it .
RORY : What exactly are you hoping for ?
HUGH : I 'm hoping to wake him up .
We 're seeing under what conditions it reengages with its environment .
( SQUEAKS )
RORY : Come on in .
We 're shocking the monkey .
( CRACKLES )
( INHALES DEEPLY )
Trying another spot .
( HUGH SIGHS )
( CRACKLES )
HUGH : Nothing . Not even at a cellular level .
Are you sure it 's not , uh , dead ?
HUGH : It 's alive . It 's just in a deep sleep .
Oh , come on , Calvin .
Wake up .
- ( CRACKLES ) - Shit !
- ( GROANS ) - RORY : What 's wrong ?
HUGH : It broke the wand .
( RAPID BEEPING )
I 'm gonna try and pull my hand out .
Do that , but just make sure to protect the glove .
HUGH : ( WHISPERS ) Shit . SHO : It 's gripping the glass .
HUGH : Okay , okay .
( HAND SQUEAKS OVER GLASS )
( GRUNTING ) Little sod .
MIRANDA : How hard is it holding on to you ?
- Like a firm handshake . - It 's fine .
It doesn 't hurt , but it 's growing strong .
- KAT : What 's the problem ? - It 's got Hugh 's hand .
His heart rate is at 165 .
- Sho , can we trust the glove ? - It 's very tight .
RORY : Glove 's not going anywhere . It 's fine .
Shit .
Okay , but just relax . Tell him to relax .
- Derry ? Derry , look at me . - Tell him to calm down .
Look at me . Relax . Just relax your hand .
- ( GROANS , PANTS ) - MIRANDA : Okay .
It 's in between my fingers .
RORY : Can I make a suggestion ?
Can I just ... Can I go in there and get him and ...
No , you 're not going to go in there .
No , of course you 're not , because we have to maintain quarantine .
- Stop . - No , I can do this . I can . I can do this . Um ...
- Can you try and distract it ? - HUGH : Yes , yes .
Um , um , I 'll see if I can interest it in the wand .
( SQUEAKING )
Come on , my favorite little Martian .
Come on .
( PANTING , TREMBLING )
Oh !
He lost interest .
( GRUNTS )
It 's got hold of my hand .
( LOW GRUNTING )
Ahh !
MIRANDA : Hugh ? RORY : Hugh ?
Hugh ?
( HUGH GASPING )
RORY : Hey , Hugh ? MIRANDA : Hugh ?
( GRUNTING )
( SQUEAKING )
( FRANTIC GRUNTING )
( GASPING ) Help me ! Help me !
DAVID : What the fuck is going on ? MIRANDA : No , no one 's going in !
- Come on . Who 's going in ? - Wait !
- Wait for fucking what ? - RORY : Screw it . I 'm going in there .
Don 't do this .
( GASPING BREATHS )
( YELLS )
I don 't give a shit about your fucking quarantine !
There 's nothing to protect you . You 're not going in there .
Who gives you the fucking jurisdiction ?
- Just open the door , Rory . - Wait , wait .
( GASPING BREATHS )
MIRANDA : You 're not going in there .
DAVID : Let him in ! MIRANDA : You 're not going in there . No .
( INDISTINCT SHOUTING )
- Wait , wait , wait . - MIRANDA : You 're not going in .
RORY : He 's out .
He 's out .
Guys , look at it .
RORY : Aw , Jesus .
DAVID : What are his vitals ?
126 and dropping .
What 's it doing ?
Holy shit .
Jesus Christ .
RORY : You guys got eyes on it anywhere ?
Okay , there . There .
( SQUEAKING )
RORY : Guys ?
( SQUEALING )
( WHIMPERS )
( CRACKLING )
RORY : Fuck this .
MIRANDA : No ! KAT : Let him go .
- RORY : Hey , buddy . - ( ALARM BLARING )
KAT : Watch his hand .
MIRANDA : There we go . SHO : It 's there .
Get him in . Adams !
( GASPING )
- Yeah . - MIRANDA : David , I need you here .
KAT : Rory , I can 't let you out .
Aw , shit .
DAVID : Oh , gosh .
MIRANDA : There we go . SHO : Hugh ? Hugh ?
- Look at me . - DAVID : Just listen to me for a second , okay ?
RORY : Hey , guys ?
MIRANDA : Sho , can you find a bandage ?
Suggestions ?
Get an oxygen candle .
- Burn it off . - Yeah , yeah , yeah .
- ( HUGH GRUNTING ) - MIRANDA : Just look at me .
Look at me . It 's fine .
( PANTING )
( WHIRS )
( GRUNTS )
RORY : Fuck . ( GRUNTS )
( EXHALES ) Okay , all right , what now ?
How do we get him out ?
We need to get Calvin back behind Firewall One ,
and once he 's there , we can pull Rory out .
RORY : Fuck this .
Permission to fucking kill the thing .
Commander ?
Kill it .
Sho ?
- Any suggestions ? - What about the incinerator ?
( STAMMERS ) I like that .
All right , genius . Here .
SHO : Close the red valve . Disengage the clamp .
Disconnect the hose .
Be careful , Rory .
- Fuck ! - SHO : There 's limited fuel .
Copy . Okay .
- Manual override . - Thank you .
Okay .
Rory , I ...
Yeah .
( FLAME WHOOSHING )
( STRAINED GRUNT )
Fuck !
SHO : You 're wasting too much fuel .
( STRAINED GRUNTING )
( YELLS ) No !
( PANTING )
Fuck .
DAVID : Rory !
Rory !
- Hey ! - ( PANTING )
KAT : Rory , stop . Stop .
MIRANDA : Rory !
( GRUNTS )
- ( GASPING BREATHS ) - ( BEEPING )
SHO : Rory ? You 're out of fuel .
( FAINT CLINKING )
- ( PANTING ) - ( FAINT THUMPING )
( PANTING )
It 's behind you !
( GRUNTING )
( GASPING WEAKLY )
( CHOKING )
- ( WHISPERS ) Jesus . - ( WHISPERS ) Fuck .
DAVID : Somebody open the fucking door !
Open the portal now ! Just open the portal .
There 's a man in there getting strangled .
- Rory ? What is he saying ? Rory ? - I can 't , no matter what 's happening .
DAVID : Kat . Kat ! We got to open the door !
- No ! No one 's going in ! It 's protocol ! - Rory ?
DAVID : What is this fucking protocol ? MIRANDA : Jordan , no !
- Just open the portal ! - Rory ?
DAVID : There 's a man dying in there ! MIRANDA : Nobody open the fucking ...
MIRANDA : Rory , look at me , look at me .
DAVID : Rory , we can 't hear you if you take your comm out .
MIRANDA : I need to see what 's happening !
DAVID : Rory ! Rory ? MIRANDA : Rory !
MIRANDA : Will you turn around ? Can you turn around ?
DAVID : There 's a man dying in there !
We can 't hear you if you take your comm out !
MIRANDA : No ! No , you are not going in !
HUGH : Help him ! DAVID : Open the door !
MIRANDA : Don 't open the door , okay ? Don 't open the door !
Stay back !
I need to see your face . Can you turn around ?
- Can you turn around ? - ( CHOKING , GASPING )
♪ ♪
( SLOW , STEADY BEEPING )
( FLATLINING TONE )
( SHUDDERING BREATH )
( SQUISHING )
♪ ♪
( SHUDDERING BREATHS )
( WHISPERS ) Guys .
Guys .
( ALARM BLARING )
Sho .
( ALARM CONTINUES BLARING )
MIRANDA : That 's so much bigger .
Jesus .
MIRANDA : Guys ?
- Sho . - MIRANDA : Guys , it 's trying to get out .
The CPU overrode us .
MIRANDA : It 's searching for a way out .
- The system won 't give me access to it . - KAT : Full manual .
MIRANDA : Shut them down , okay ?
How smart is this thing ?
It feels the airflow .
I can 't control them all at once .
KAT : Then shut them one by one .
Seal the lab .
- Just shut it down ! Shut it down now ! - KAT : We are on it .
( BEEPING )
( FAINT , MUFFLED THUMPING )
( MUFFLED THUMPING CONTINUES )
Guys , it 's gone .
- It got out . - KAT : Where did it go ?
DAVID : Could be anywhere now .
MIRANDA : Firewall Two has failed .
( BREATH SHUDDERING )
♪ ♪
DAVID : Kat .
We need to reestablish quarantine .
KAT : And get a distress call out .
Control , this is Station .
Station for Control .
The specimen 's location is unknown .
It is to be considered hostile and deadly .
Our intent is to isolate and destroy it in compliance with protocol .
We 'll continue said course of action unless otherwise instructed .
- Please acknowledge and advise ... - Kat ? Kat . We lost them .
- How much of that went out ? - Some .
I think .
There is no way to be sure .
Looks like communications just failed .
Can we talk to each other ?
David . It 's Kat .
Do you copy ?
DAVID : Go for David .
So , we 've lost contact with Earth .
( SIGHS ) I don 't think ... Wait .
Yes , outside communications are down .
- Could the sprinklers affect comms ? - SHO : No .
They 're independent systems .
Can we run a diagnostic from here ?
( CLICKING , BEEPING )
SHO : The transmitter has failed .
But we have to go outside to access it and get Earth back online .
Then I have to walk .
Let me .
No .
After Rory , I 'm best qualified for walk-and-repair .
DAVID : This is not protocol .
It 's way too risky for you to go out there and
fix the comms .
We don 't know where Calvin is .
You haven 't had your nitrogen detox .
Your health is my responsibility .
- I 'll be fine . - Yeah .
What is it you say ?
" Slow is fast , " right ?
Yeah . Slow to go fast .
Yeah . Well , that 's out the window .
We can escape in the lifeboats .
Earth is the responsibility . Nothing goes down to the planet .
It was stipulated . In writing .
DAVID : What are you talking about ? What was stipulated in writing ?
What was stipulated ?
KAT : David , first things first .
When we 're back in touch with Control , we 'll turn our attention to Calvin .
Don 't worry .
( INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER COMM )
MIRANDA : Rate , 61 beats a minute .
Pressure , 97 over 53 .
I 'd hate to see you relaxed .
DAVID : But she is relaxed . Aren 't you , Kat ?
SHO : Suit 's running warm .
KAT : Like Siberia in summer .
( LOW GASP )
I 'm at the transmitter .
Commencing on-site diagnostic .
It 's overheated .
I can tell .
SHO : How ?
I see scorching .
I want to check the coolant levels .
Is it possible Calvin could have gotten into coolant ?
Possible .
We have to know .
- There is the issue . - HUGH : Commander ?
It 's bone-dry .
HUGH : Calvin is a carbon-based organism .
It needs food , water , and oxygen , just like us .
We have to consider the possibility it consumed the coolant for food .
David , could you list all the water sources aboard ?
Pure or otherwise .
DAVID : Uh , there 's plenty of drinking water ,
there 's coolant for the comms , coolant for the CPU ...
Um ... There 's coolant for the spacesuits .
- ( GASPS ) - MIRANDA : Commander ?
KAT : Calvin just came out . It grabbed my suit .
It 's bigger .
It 's trying to get in .
SHO : Trust your suit .
MIRANDA : Can it breathe out there ? HUGH : No .
But it might be able to store oxygen for a period of time .
I 'm closing the valve .
( PANTING , TREMBLING )
It 's squeezing .
HUGH : Kat . Kat , are you okay ?
Yes . The suit 's thick enough .
It 's twisting up your leg . Go . Go to the airlock now .
Aw , fuck this . I 'm headed for the airlock . I 'm burning this fucker off .
SHO : Kat , focus on meeting David .
We 'll worry about the comms later .
Sho ?
There 's liquid in the helmet .
Calvin must have broken my coolant loop .
Kat , there is enough coolant .
KAT : Yes , I know .
- I know . - ( FOOTSTEPS THUMPING )
David , meet me at the airlock .
What ? Yeah . Go , go , go !
KAT : It 's squeezing harder .
DAVID : Calvin cracked the coolant system in her suit .
HUGH : Commander , Calvin knows exactly what it 's doing .
It 's growing smarter .
The liquid , it 's blocking my vision .
I don 't have time .
I 've got to jump .
- SHO : Kat , the tether won 't reach . - I 'm unclipping .
- SHO : Kat ? - No comments !
I 've got to jump .
( GRUNTS )
- ( RUMBLING ) - ( GRUNTS )
( GASPS )
( MUFFLED GRUNTING )
MIRANDA : David , I 've taken Kat off the channel .
Look , she 's not gonna tell you this ,
but her heart is beating out of her chest . She 's drowning .
So just be prepared , she may not be rational .
DAVID : Copy that .
Sho , I have no time for EVA .
I 'm using the launch suit .
- SHO : It 's not designed for this . - I know .
- There 's not enough protection . - I know . Don 't worry .
MIRANDA : Kat is less than a minute out . DAVID : Vent the airlock .
- SHO : What about decompression ? - Just do it .
- It 's gonna hurt . - Come on , do it !
- Is your helmet sealed ? - Sho !
( WHOOSHING )
( SCREAMING )
( PAINED GRUNTING )
( LOW , GASPING BREATHS )
SHO : Guys , we are running out of time .
( GRUNTS )
( MUFFLED GRUNTING )
DAVID : Kat , Kat ! Don 't swallow it .
It 's toxic , okay ?
I need you to help me open the valve .
We 're gonna do this together .
Okay ?
- ( LOUD GASPING ) - I 'm gonna pull down ,
and you 're gonna go clockwise from your side .
- ( GASPING BREATHS ) - Okay ?
DAVID : There you go .
Good , good , good .
( LABORED BREATHING )
Don 't worry about Calvin .
We 're gonna get you inside , and we 're gonna get it off .
( GRUNTING )
( GASPING ) David .
DAVID : Kat ?
No , no , no . Clockwise from your side .
- ( WHEEZING GROAN ) - Clockwise from your side .
Kat , come on .
- Miranda ? - MIRANDA : Yeah , I 'm here .
She 's fighting me ! She 's turned her lever the wrong way .
Pull down ...
( CREAKING )
( STRAINED GRUNTING )
Kat . You 're fighting me , Kat . Come on .
We got to do it together , now .
- Come on . Kat , come on , please . - MIRANDA : David .
DAVID : Kat !
- Kat . Kat ! - DAVID : Look at me !
Just pull on the lever ! Okay ?
- ( BEEPING ) - Kat , come on ! Come on !
Just pull down on the lever !
( MUFFLED GASPING )
MIRANDA : David ... DAVID : Kat !
Come on , you can do this !
MIRANDA : David , she 's doing it deliberately .
( FRANTIC GASPING )
Come on !
- ( GASPING QUIETS ) - Kat !
- Kat ! - David , stop .
Stop .
She 's not letting Calvin back in here .
Kat ?
( QUIET CHOKING )
Commander .
♪ ♪
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( WHISPERS ) Kat , Kat ...
♪ ♪
( SOBBING QUIETLY )
What is going on ?
( TREMBLING ) What is going on ?
( SOBBING )
♪ ♪
( MIRANDA SOBBING )
HUGH : Guys , guys , do you copy ?
MIRANDA : Yeah .
- Yeah , I copy . - Okay , okay , um ...
Let 's keep it together .
We may have ... We may have an opportunity here .
Calvin 's ability to survive in that vacuum and temperature
is astonishing .
But he can 't live much longer out there .
Sho . Sho .
Are you sure that we 've lost all communication with Earth ?
I am sure .
All right , then we have to keep it out there .
MIRANDA : We have a new firewall .
David , can you see it ?
DAVID : I 'll see . Um ...
- Sho . - SHO : Yes ?
Can you re-flood the airlock ?
( AIR HISSING )
You tell me when .
SHO : Okay .
( SNIFFLING )
DAVID : Did she close that valve ?
MIRANDA : Yeah , yeah , she closed it .
Okay .
What other way could it get in ?
The thrusters .
The manifolds in the thruster nozzles .
If it tries one , we could blast it off .
But we 'd have to know which .
DAVID : It 's too dark . I can 't see anything .
- Shit . - MIRANDA : There must be some way .
Thruster sensors .
If it climbs in the nozzle , the temperature should move .
Should .
All right .
( GASPS )
- There . - Thruster two firing .
( RUMBLING )
Miranda , can you reach Tranquility ?
( GRUNTS )
We missed . Cut it .
Guys , it 's heading toward ... No , wait !
No , no , it 's heading towards the lab . It 's fast .
DAVID : I 'm sorry , guys , I can 't see .
HUGH : It 's okay , we 're watching .
- Kibo . - Thruster three firing .
( RUMBLING )
( WHISPERS ) Come on .
Please , please .
Quest this time .
- David , can you see ? - DAVID : No , I 'm ...
- Thruster five . - Sorry . I 'm sorry , I can 't ...
( RUMBLING )
( GRUNTING )
- MIRANDA : Sho ? - ( RAPID BEEPING )
( ALARM BLARING )
- ( ALARM STOPS ) - DAVID : What was that ?
We 've burned through too much fuel .
- There . - SHO : We were already low after the Pilgrim .
Doc , listen , all this thrusting , we 've placed ourselves into decaying orbit .
- DAVID : Shit . - We 'll reach atmosphere soon
if I don 't get us back to stable .
And I 'll need the rest of the fuel to do it ,
- if we even have that much . - No . David ?
David , we can 't risk Calvin riding us down into the atmosphere , okay ?
But I don 't know ... Could it survive that ?
HUGH : We don 't know .
It 's already gone well beyond
what any living organism should be able to survive .
( PANTING )
MIRANDA : If it 's between letting it in here or letting it down there ,
we let it in here .
Where are you ?
♪ ♪
HUGH : We 've just let it back in here .
( RUMBLING )
SHO : Moving us back into stable orbit .
These creatures could have dominated Mars for hundreds of millions of years .
But now we know that they hibernate with a loss of atmosphere .
If we deprive it of air ,
retreat in Tranquility , and seal ourselves off ...
MIRANDA : And vent the rest of the station .
Exactly .
No life support , no life .
MIRANDA : Right .
Okay , Hugh and I will sweep from Quest east .
And , um , you and Sho scour the poles and , uh , lock off each compartment .
( BEEPING )
( METALLIC CREAKING )
♪ ♪
( GASPING SOFTLY )
( WHIRRING , CLACKING )
♪ ♪
( RIPPING )
( HISSES )
SHO : ( PANTING ) It will take about four hours to vent all oxygen .
MIRANDA : What do we do till then ? DAVID : We wait .
You okay ?
Derry , look at me .
- ( WEAKLY ) Hmm ? - You okay ?
I 'm fine .
I remember the day the Challenger blew up .
They took us out of school early , I remember that day .
It 's hard to watch people die .
♪ ♪
Like , uh ...
Fireworks .
HUGH : " Up , up "
" the long , delirious , burning blue "
" I 've topped the wind-swept heights with ease and grace "
Best eulogy ever .
DAVID : Hmm .
Rory says ,
" Don 't give me a eulogy . "
" Give me a parachute . "
( HUGH CHUCKLING )
( SIGHS )
He was my buddy .
( WHISPERS ) It 's my fault .
It 's all my fault .
Maybe it was your fault , maybe it was my fault , maybe ...
I don 't know , it doesn 't matter , does it ?
Getting this thing on board was a risk , and we knew it from the beginning .
I took it .
HUGH : It 's just surviving .
Life 's very existence requires destruction .
Calvin doesn 't hate us .
But he has to kill us
in order to survive .
DAVID : Hugh .
- Hugh . Hugh . - Hugh .
( HUGH GROANS )
DAVID : All right , all right .
- Hey . - Derry ?
Hugh ?
I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry , because of all the ...
- Hugh ? - Hugh ?
( RAPID BEEPING )
Hugh ?
DAVID : Hugh ? There 's no output .
God , get the defib .
- Get him back . - Okay .
- Get him down . - MIRANDA : I 'll strap him in .
DAVID : Take off the sling , okay ? SHO : Yeah .
MIRANDA : Sho , get the ACLS kit and the defibrillator .
- ( FLATLINING TONE ) - DAVID : Shit .
SHO : Here .
MIRANDA : Prep the defibrillator and get the shocks down .
MIRANDA : 360 joules . DAVID : Yeah .
DAVID : Copy , 360 joules .
Charging . Clear .
( THUMP )
DAVID : Charging . Shooting . MIRANDA : Still fibrillating .
Just stack the shocks if you have to .
- Go , 360 . - All right . Clear .
DAVID : ( WHISPERS ) Shit .
- Nothing . - Go again , 360 .
- Go again . Hit him . - Clear .
- DAVID : All right . - ( THUMP )
All right , all right . I got output .
- Yeah . - Okay .
Okay , sinus rate 98 BPM .
DAVID : You really scared me there , buddy .
- ( BREATHING HEAVILY ) - David ?
David ?
( WHISPERS ) Fuck .
What is this ?
DAVID : Stabilizing .
( ALL GASPING )
Get the plasma cutter .
MIRANDA : Calvin 's feeding off his leg .
DAVID : Shit !
- ( ELECTRONIC WHIR ) - Miranda !
( MIRANDA GASPS )
DAVID : Go . Get out of here .
Let 's go !
Miranda , let 's go ! Pull it away from Hugh .
Sho .
- We 'll come back for him ! - Miranda ! Come on ! Let 's go !
DAVID : Sho !
No !
Sho !
No ! Shit .
Hey , guys ?
( FEEDBACK SQUEALING )
Shit .
♪ ♪
( CRACKLING , CREAKING )
( HUGH EXHALES )
Calvin ?
- MIRANDA : We don 't know where he is . - ( HUGH SIGHS )
- Where 's Sho ? - MIRANDA : He 'll be fine .
We stopped all oxygen venting in the station .
( HUGH GROANING )
Lift me up .
( HUGH EXHALES )
MIRANDA : Okay .
Okay .
HUGH : ( WHISPERS ) Oh , Miranda .
♪ ♪
( BREATHING WEAKLY )
I 'm up .
( SLOW , STEADY BEEPING )
( FLATLINING TONE )
♪ ♪
( SOBBING QUIETLY )
- ( PANTING ) - ( SPEAKING JAPANESE )
I 'm coming home , Mei .
MIRANDA : I know what I feel is not scientific .
It 's not rational .
I feel hate .
I feel pure ...
fucking
hate for that thing .
( ELECTRONIC PINGING )
( PINGING )
Calvin .
How is that moving like that ?
He must have swallowed the marker on Derry 's leg .
Yeah .
( PINGING CONTINUES )
We can track him .
♪ ♪
( PINGING )
( PINGING CONTINUES )
♪ ♪
( MIRANDA GASPS )
DAVID : Let 's kill this thing . Venting Zarya now .
( BEEPING )
( MIRANDA PANTING )
Okay , it 's suffocating .
- How long do you think that 's gonna take ? - I don 't know .
- ( ALARM BEEPING ) - Shit .
AUTOMATED VOICE : Proximity alert . Proximity alert .
Proximity alert . Proximity alert .
Proximity ...
They 're coming .
Kat 's distress call must have reached Earth .
Wait , where are they docking ?
Shit .
- Looks like Zarya . - Jesus , that 's where Calvin is .
Station to Soyuz .
Station to Soyuz , do you copy ?
- Station to Soyuz , do you copy ? - MIRANDA : Try the flashlight .
DAVID : ( WHISPERS ) Come on , come on .
They can 't see this .
Must be too reflective .
- ( GRUNTS ) - ( RUMBLING )
( GASPING BREATHS )
( RUMBLING CONTINUES )
DAVID : Shit .
What the fuck are they doing ?
David .
David !
They 're not coming to rescue us .
It 's Firewall Three .
What ?
Firewall One was the box .
And Firewall Two was the lab .
And Firewall Three is the station .
But we have a new firewall .
- What are you saying ? - MIRANDA : They don 't know that .
And if Firewall One or Two fail , they have two choices .
They can contain , or they expel .
They 're pushing us out to deep space .
They cannot risk Calvin reaching Earth .
That was my protocol .
I insisted from the beginning , and the committee agreed .
They all put their names to it .
The list is as long as your arm .
Now , protecting firewalls is my job ,
and if we would have succeeded , we could have gone home .
And if we failed ...
Wait for me , Mei .
( BEEPING )
( CLICKING , BEEPING )
DAVID : Sho . Oh , he thinks it 's a rescue .
Oh , God . He 's heading towards Calvin .
We have to stop him .
( PANTING )
Sho !
Sho , can you hear us ?
( STRAINED GRUNT )
♪ ♪
( METALLIC THUD )
DAVID : Sho !
( INDISTINCT SHOUTING )
MIRANDA : Sho !
( SHOUTING CONTINUES )
( MUFFLED BOOMING )
( YELLING )
- ( GRUNTING ) - ( BEEPING )
( BEEPING )
( YELLING , GROANING )
DAVID : Sho !
- Miranda ! - Sho !
Sho ?
- DAVID : Sho ! - Take my hand , Sho !
- Don 't let go , Sho ! - ( SHO GRUNTING )
( GRUNTS )
MIRANDA : No !
No ! No , don 't let go !
Sho ! No , Sho ! No !
- No ! - SHO : Let go !
- No ! - No !
No ! Sho ! Sho !
( BOTH GRUNTING )
Miranda !
( GRUNTING )
MIRANDA : No !
- Come on ! - No !
Miranda !
( GASPS )
Miranda ! Let 's go !
( RUMBLING )
( DEEP CREAKING )
The CPU is still up . It 's a miracle .
We 're , uh ...
We 're losing life support .
The temperature is dropping rapidly .
Atmosphere is venting from everywhere , and I don 't know how to stop it .
Okay , how much time do we have ?
In here ? Uh , two hours , maybe an hour 45 ...
But it , uh ...
- What ? - Fuck .
- Fuck ! - What ? What is it ? What ?
We 're , uh ...
We 're not moving into space . The opposite .
All that fucked-up thrusting , we 're decaying again .
What ?
Sho has a subroutine here .
Um ...
Without any correction in course , which we don 't have any fuel for anyway , um ...
We 'll hit the atmosphere in , uh ...
39 minutes .
We 're not gonna survive reentry .
( WRY CHUCKLE )
Calvin could .
( TREMBLING BREATHING )
♪ ♪
( MIRANDA SHIVERING )
It 's so cold .
( SHIVERING STOPS )
DAVID : Hmm .
- ( CHUCKLES SOFTLY ) - Mmm .
My father used to read this to me when I was a kid .
♪ ♪
( SHIVERING SOFTLY )
" Good night , room . "
" Good night , moon . "
" Good night , cow jumping over the moon . "
( SOFT , TREMBLING LAUGH )
DAVID : " Good night , light . "
" And the red balloon . "
( SNIFFLES )
♪ ♪
" Good night , nobody . "
( DAVID SNIFFLES )
( CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
MIRANDA : I remember when I saw my first picture of Earth .
And I asked my father where all those ...
All those lines were .
The borders .
( BOTH CHUCKLE SOFTLY )
( WHISPERS ) I really miss him .
♪ ♪
Good night , moon .
Good night , stars .
Good night , air .
( MIRANDA SHIVERING )
Bait .
Calvin needs oxygen to survive .
With the 02 levels so low in the rest of the ship ,
it will be drawn to the oxygen candles .
- We can use them as bait . - Yeah .
There are two lifeboats , A and B ,
both set to default entry trajectory .
You press the button , they autopilot themselves to the surface ,
unless somebody ...
Somebody overrides them from the inside .
I use the oxygen candles to lure Calvin into Boat A.
I close the hatch . I press the button to give me full manual control .
And if I can hold the stick , I can override the flight path .
And if I hold it long enough ,
I can avoid reentry .
( STUTTERING ) You fly out into deep space .
With Calvin . Yes .
( STAMMERING ) Meanwhile , you get into Boat B ,
you press the button , and if there are no complications ,
- then it 'd take you back home . - No .
No , we should lure Calvin together .
- No , Miranda . - Yeah .
That doesn 't make any sense .
Why ?
The lifeboats are meant for one person .
And this has been your plan all along .
To make sure that , that creature doesn 't get to Earth .
Then I should be Plan A.
No , I 'm a pilot .
You 're Plan B.
Listen , listen .
I belong up here .
DAVID : Hmm .
I don 't want to go back down to eight billion of those motherfuckers .
- ( CRYING LAUGH ) - ( SNIFFLES )
I need you to say you trust me .
Yeah ?
I do .
I trust you .
DAVID : Wait here . I 'll signal you .
( WHIRRING , CLACK )
( SHIVERING )
♪ ♪
( EXHALES SHARPLY )
( COUGHING )
( RAPID BEEPING )
( BEEPING CONTINUES )
( CLATTERING NEARBY )
( SHIVERING )
( GASPS ) Hey ! Shit !
Whoa .
( GASPING BREATHS )
Shit !
( SHIVERING )
( BEEPING )
( PANTING )
Fuck .
( GRUNTING )
( GASPING BREATHS )
( GASPING )
Okay .
This is Mission Specialist Dr. David A. Jordan
commanding Soyuz Lifeboat A , 2233 UTC .
ISS has entered catastrophic orbital decay .
Initiating emergency escape sequence in five ,
four , three ,
two , one .
( LOUD RUMBLING )
( GASPING )
( ELECTRONIC BEEPING )
♪ ♪
( BEEPING )
Come on , Miranda , get going .
( GRUNTS )
( BEEPS )
DAVID : Initiating manual override .
( PANTING )
( BEEPING )
This is Dr. Miranda North ,
black box recording in case of death upon reentry .
The creature killed four of the six ISS astronauts ,
with a fifth , Dr. David Jordan ,
presumed dead , carrying it out into deep space .
My five colleagues all sacrificed themselves to maintain the firewall , so , please ,
honor them for giving everything to this cause .
Mars life-forms should be considered hostile .
Do not underestimate their intelligence and their adaptive capabilities .
Now , we did not learn how to restrain or eliminate it ,
but if this creature ever reaches Earth ,
use every available resource to destroy it ,
or you will risk all human life .
( ALARM BLARING )
( ALARM STOPS )
( GRUNTS )
( GRUNTING )
( PAINED GROAN )
( SCREAMS )
( GRUNTING )
( STRAINED GRUNTING )
( YELLING )
( GRUNTS )
♪ ♪
( SOFTLY ) You can do it . You can do it .
You can do it .
Come on !
( WHOOSHING )
( BIRD SQUAWKING )
( MAN SPEAKING VIETNAMESE )
( SPEAKS VIETNAMESE )
DAVID : No , no , no . No !
MIRANDA : ( SCREAMING ) No ! No !
No !
( BEEPING RAPIDLY )
No ! No !
- DAVID : No ! No ! - ( MEN SPEAKING VIETNAMESE )
( BOTH GRUNTING )
No !
No , no , no !
No , no , no , no !
♪ ♪
When I die and they lay me to rest
Gonna go to the place that 's the best
When I lay me down to die
Goin ' up to the spirit in the sky
That 's where I 'm gonna go when I die
When I die and they lay me to rest
I 'm gonna go to the place that 's the best
Go to the place that 's the best
♪ ♪